MIGUEL ANGEL HERNANDEZ MELO

Senior Software Engineer

+527821039059 • miguelhem@gmail.com • linkedin: @miguelhem • Guadalara, Mexico

Summary

As a Software Engineer with more than six years of direct experience, I specialize in the design and development of applications across diverse industries. My proficiency centers on leading full-stack development projects, focusing on front-end technologies, to deliver solutions that are both responsive and centered on user needs. I possess a strong ability to guide development teams through the full software development life cycle, consistently applying industry best practices guaranteeing top-tier end product.

Experience

Globant Remote - Guadalara, Mexico

Senior Software Engineer - Team lead

2022 - Present

- Led a team of front-end developers to migrate two legacy AngularJS projects to React, introducing best practices and comprehensive end-to-end testing to ensure a smooth and reliable transition.
- Contributed to diverse internal projects utilizing a variety of front-end technologies such as Angular, React with TypeScript, and React Native.
- Defined the architectural structure and establish development best practices for a newly created Angular project (version 17 and 18).

EPAM Systems Remote - Guadalara, Mexico
Senior Software Engineer 2021 - 2022

- Proposed innovative approaches, architectures, and dependencies for client websites.
- Developed websites and user interfaces for cruises, restaurants, and hotels using standard HTML/SCSS, aligning with stakeholder requirements
- Optimized legacy code, ensuring adherence to best coding practices with a focus on performance
- Developed UI pages created for a CMS using .NET technologies
- Migrated from ¡Query to Vanilla JavaScript and React.js

Tata Consultancy Services

Remote - Guadalara, Mexico

Software Engineer 2019 - 2021

- Designed a frontend application utilizing Angular 2+
- · Collaborated with the planning and development team to review application features and strategize future enhancements
- Offered expert technical support for the development, installation, and maintenance of business applications
- · Ensured seamless integration of new features with existing systems for enhanced user experience

Freelancer Remote

Web Developer 2017 - 2019

- Developed front-end solutions, significantly enhancing system performance and operational efficiency within the companies I worked on.
- Management of databases in order to maintain the performance of the application in an optimum behavior.
- Performed unit and integrations tests to ensure systems requirements.

Education

Universidad Virtual del Estado de Guanajuato

Computer Systems Engineering

Tecnologico Nacional de Mexico

Hydrocarbon Engineering

Connect Internation School

Business English

Mexico

2020 - 2024

Mexico

Toronto, CA

2018

Skills

Agile · Javascript · Typescript · Angular · React · Vue · React Native · JQuery · Bootstrap · Material UI · CSS · HTML · SCSS · LESS · Jest · Karma · Jasmine · Cypress · Storybook · Node · .NET · MongoDB · PostgreSQL · Git · Gitlab · Github · Azure Devops · Docker · ClickUp · Jira · Al Tools